<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:23:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Marianas Web</title>
      <link>/posts/marianas-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:23:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/marianas-web/</guid>
      <description>During this article I will explore this topic from my perspective as a networking person. Does it exist? Is it feasible? Let&amp;rsquo;s look into it
What is the Marianas Web? It is a fictional layer of the &amp;lsquo;internet&amp;rsquo; that has following key points:
Can&amp;rsquo;t be / wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet proven to exist Can only be accessed using &amp;ldquo;Polymeric Falcighol Derivation&amp;rdquo; which requires Quantum Computers You&amp;rsquo;re probably asking yourself, what the fuck is &amp;ldquo;Polymeric Falcighol Derivation&amp;rdquo;.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;During this article I will explore this topic from my perspective as a networking person.
Does it exist? Is it feasible? Let&amp;rsquo;s look into it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-marianas-web&#34;&gt;What is the Marianas Web?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a &lt;strong&gt;fictional&lt;/strong&gt; layer of the &amp;lsquo;internet&amp;rsquo; that has following key points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t be / wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet proven to exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can only be accessed using &amp;ldquo;Polymeric Falcighol Derivation&amp;rdquo; which requires Quantum Computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably asking yourself, what the fuck is &amp;ldquo;Polymeric Falcighol Derivation&amp;rdquo;.
Well, to this day I still do. Here is the explanation from Urban Dictionary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complex algorithm that is often associated with the Marina Web (Level 5 Web); needed to access said web. The Marina Web is the deepest part of the internet and is only rumored to exist. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;br&gt;
Many often write it off as a hoax however no evidence proofing or dis-proofing exists
However the computing power/knowledge needed to process and compute the algorithm is quantum computing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=polymeric%20falcighol%20derivation&#34;&gt;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=polymeric%20falcighol%20derivation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will call it out as bs&lt;/strong&gt;, probably just a term some skid created, but the key point is that it requires a quantum computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-does-it-need-a-quantum-computer-for&#34;&gt;What does it need a quantum computer for?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quantum processor gives the ability to represent the values 0, 1 and values in between both with Qubits.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m not deep into Quantum computing, but I can abstract this concept and go further into the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needing the quantum computers for computationally intensive tasks required to complete before / during sending network traffic on the Marianas web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needing the quantum computers because data is sent as Qubits encoded on a cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;qubit-based-network-traffic&#34;&gt;Qubit-based network traffic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we send network traffic, it will be represented by a change in voltage.&lt;br&gt;
Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For 10BASE-T or 100BASE-TX, the data is usually carried on pairs 2 and 3 (often the blue and green pairs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; is sent, the voltage may transition from +2.5V to -2.5V on one wire of the pair, and from -2.5V to +2.5V on the other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a &amp;lsquo;0&amp;rsquo; is sent, the voltage levels would remain constant at their last state, either +2.5V or -2.5V.
Bit encoding standard &amp;ldquo;PAM-5&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, there is no network connecting quantum processors, or quantum repeaters deployed outside a lab.
And that is basically the problem.
Since there is no standard, basically any network of Quantum computers that is under NDA and Top Secret restrictions would be &amp;ldquo;The Marianas Web&amp;rdquo; wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_network#Quantum_internet&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_network#Quantum_internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, since all Routers on the internet use IP, Ethernet and so on, and encode their data as Bits on the cable, not Qubits, it would be simply IMPOSSIBLE that there is any &amp;ldquo;Hidden Network&amp;rdquo; INSIDE of the Internet that communicates with Qubits as Data Unit. It would require it&amp;rsquo;s entirely own Protocol Stack that is not yet supported by any Routers on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;computationally-intensive-tasks&#34;&gt;Computationally intensive tasks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the only way I see how it would make sense that there is a hidden network on the internet. It would be feasible and would be using Protocols we know to transfer the data, but the data would be encrypted with algorithms that are not publicly available and probably also not standardized.
In that case the Marianas Web would be a layer of the internet, where people send data encrypted with their Quantum Computers down in their basement (cuz everyone has them right) and the communications would be perfectly visible, but the content impossible to see by todays standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users for this type of network would be governments and highly, highly sophisticated organizations / criminal organizations.
The most secure government secrets would be transferred here and noone will be able to decrypt it for some decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will most probably also use their own protocols above Layer 3, since Routers on the internet don&amp;rsquo;t look further than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a network that noone knows about is an interesting idea, especially since it would be right at our feet.
However the way it is described doesn&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
